

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- -SQL (MySQL, Postgres)
- -Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikitlearn, Keras)
- -Microsoft
- -l atex
- -MATLAB
- -Git
- -R
- -AWS Athena(SQL)
- -Java
- -Power BI
- -Tableau
- -C, C++ and C#

### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- -Ability to analyze complex technical information
- -Reliable and professional
- -Detail orientation
- -Time management
- -Team player
- -Fast learner
- -Motivated

### WEBSITE

 https://aovaldes2.github.io/Alejandro-O-Valdes-Portfolio/index.html

## CONTACT

- +34 631 327 628
  - linkedin.com/in/aovaldes2



aovaldes2@gmail.com



Leganés, Madrid

### LANGUAGES

- Native: Spanish
- Fluent: English

# ALEJANDRO O. VALDÉS

# DATA SCIENTIST

### **ABOUT**

Data Scientist graduated in mathematics with multiple postgraduate studies and experience in education and as a data analyst. With a team-oriented attitude, I am always eager to contribute with my abilities in programming and applied mathematics.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

PRIVATE TEACHER (MATH, PROGRAMMING) Self - employed | Sept 2020 - Jul 2022

DATA ANALYST (TRAINEESHIP)

Openbank | Mar 2020 - Aug 2020

- Migration project: Analysis of controls and resolution of incidents obtained in the datacleasing process.
- Support in the BBOO department T&O processes: Definition of metrics, KPIs and visualizations of operational process data. Dashboard monitoring for bottleneck detection, incidents and improvements.
- Documentation of the data models developed.

### MATH TEACHER

University of Havana| Sept 2016 - Mar 2017

 Mathematics I degree in Food Science: Teaching of the subject and elaboration of exams.

Technological University of Havana | Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

 Mathematics I in Mechanical Engineering; Mathematics II in Biomedical Engineering; Mathematics IV in Electrical Engineering and Numerical Mathematics in Telecommunications Engineering: Teaching of the subject and elaboration of exams.

## EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE. MATHEMATICS

University of Havana | 2010 - 2014 GPA 9.2

MASTER OF SCIENCE, MATHEMATICAL ENGINEERING

University Carlos III of Madrid | 2018 - 2020 [In Progress]

**BOOTCAMP DATA SCIENCE** 

The Bridge Digital Talent Accelerator | 2021



### **APTITUDES TÉCNICAS**

- -SQL (MySQL, Postgres)
- -Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikitlearn, Keras)
- -Microsoft
- -Latex
- -MATLAR
- -Git
- -R
- -AWS Athena(SQL)
- -Java
- -Power BI
- -Tableau
- -C, C++ and C#

# APTITUDES PERSONALES

- -Capacidad para analizar información técnica compleja
- -Confiable y profesional
- -Orientación al detalle
- -Gestión del tiempo
- -Trabajo en equipo
- -Facilidad para el aprendizaje

### WEBSITE

 https://aovaldes2.github.io/Alejandro-O-Valdes-Portfolio/index.html

### CONTACTO



- +34 631 327 628
- linkedin.com/in/aovaldes2



- aovaldes2@gmail.com
- Leganés, Madrid

### **IDIOMAS**

- Nativo: Español
- Fluido: Inglés

# ALEJANDRO O. VALDÉS

## DATA SCIENTIST

### **PERFIL**

Data Scientist graduado en matemáticas con múltiples estudios de postgrado que dispone de experiencia en el sector educativo y como analista de datos. Orientado al trabajo en equipo, siempre estoy dispuesto a contribuir con mis habilidades en la programación y las matemáticas aplicadas.

### **EXPERIENCIA LABORAL**

PROFESOR PARTICULAR (MATEMÁTICAS, PROGRAMACIÓN) Trabjador por cuenta propia | Sept 2020 - Jul 2022

DATA ANALYST (BECARIO)

Openbank | Mar 2020 - Ago 2020

- Proyecto de migración: Análisis de controles y resolución de incidencias obtenidos en el proceso de datacleasing.
- Soporte en el departamento BBOO Procesos T&O: Definición de métricas, KPIs y visualizaciones de datos de procesos operativos. Monitorización de cuadros de mando para detección de cuellos de botella, incidencias y mejoras.
- Documentación de los modelos de datos desarrollados.

### PROFESOR UNIVERSITARIO DE MATEMÁTICAS

Universidad de la Habanal Sept 2016 - Mar 2017

 Matemáticas I en el grado Ciencias Alimentarias: Impartición de la asignatura y elaboración de exámenes.

Universidad Tecnológica de La Habana | Ago 2014 - Ago 2016

 Matemáticas I en Ing. Mecánica; Matemáticas II en Ing. Biomédica; Matemáticas IV en Ing. Eléctrica y Matemática Numérica en Ing.en Telecomunicaciones: Impartición de las clases prácticas y elaboración de exámenes

# HISTORIAL ACADÉMICO

LICENCIATURA EN MATEMÁTICAS

Universidad de la Habana | 2010 - 2014 N.G: 9.2

MÁSTER EN INGENIERÍA MATEMÁTICA

University Carlos III of Madrid | 2018 - 2020 [En Progreso]

BOOTCAMP DATA SCIENCE

The Bridge Digital Talent Accelerator | 2021